《智能緝兇》前情提要
Previously on Intelligence...
要是知道你造了第二塊芯片
What would your government do to you
你的政府會怎么處置你
if they learned you made a second chip?
誰在那兒
Who's there?
等一下  站住
Wait! Stop!
你是美辰
You're Mei Chen.
裝了第二塊芯片的人
You're the one with the chip.
世界不是完美的
It's not a perfect world.
但我們至少可以讓它進步  爸爸
We can make it better, dad.
一個偉大的人教給我的
A great man taught me that.
你需要我
You need me.
你感覺得到
You can feel it.
你是亞當  而我是夏娃
You are Adam... And I'm Eve.
你不是夏娃  甜心
You're not Eve, sweetheart.
你是撒旦
You're the Serpent.
文德爾酒店
華盛頓特區
謝謝你來見我  非常感激
Thanks for coming to see me. I appreciate it.
我時間不多  哈奇
I don't have much time here, Hatch.
你現在是聯調局的副局長了  約瑟夫
You're the deputy director of the FBI now, Joseph.
你不會后悔為此事騰出時間的
You want to -- you want to make time for this.
沒事  我要了點吃的
Oh, no. It's all right. I ordered up a little food.
旅途漫漫
It was a long flight in.
又開始喝酒了嗎  哈奇
Drinking again, Hatch?
我沒有點香檳
I didn't order the champagne.
香檳是酒店經理贈送的
The champagne is courtesy of the hotel manager.
請坐
Please, sit.
請
Please.
聽著
Look.
我來僅僅是看在我們交情的份上
I'm only here 'cause we have history.
我知道
I know that.
但我在電話里說過  這次我有證據
But like I said on the phone, I have proof this time.
得了吧  哈奇
Come on, Hatch,
我見過你的證據  黎巴嫩的那個老太太嗎
I've seen your proof before. That old woman from Lebanon?
她是他們外交部的一名秘書
She was a secretary in their foreign office.
她親眼看見了通往華盛頓的電纜
She saw the cables to Washington with her own eyes.
我們跟她談話時
And when we talked to her,
她連自己的名字都不記得
she couldn't remember her own name.
他們就在這里  約瑟夫
They're here, Joseph.
他們已經在這里了
They've been here,
靜候時機  就像潛藏在草叢里的蛇
lying in wait like snakes in the grass.
這是什么玩意兒
What the hell is that?
我說過了  證據
I told you -- proof.
證明"漫布"是真的
Proof that the Flood is real.
鏈接它  看一眼
Plug it in and take a look.
如果這又只是你的一個瘋狂臆測
If this is another one of your crazy ideas --
我用了二十年時間弄的
I've been working on this for 20 years.
你就看吧
Just look at it.
這是什么
What is this?
這就是他們
It's them.
六虎隊
The Six Tigers
以及他們的代號清單
and a list of their code names
還有足夠的證明文件
and enough documentation to prove it.
不知道他們的長相  真名
Without their faces, their real names,
我又能怎么做
come on, what am I supposed to do?
展開官方調查
Open an official investigation.
小酌一點香檳應該沒問題吧
I think a tiny sip of this champagne might be warranted.
還有什么人知道這件事
Who else knows about this?
天知地知  你知我知
I do and now you do.
歡迎加入戰場
Welcome to the war.
加布里爾
Gabriel!
不會吧
Really?
加布里爾
Gabriel?
Gabriel.
萊利  你怎么來了
Riley, what -- what are you doing here?
接你去上班
Picking you up for work.
你不會敲門嗎
Don't you knock?
你居然沒聽到我敲門
How could you not hear me?
怎么了  你病了嗎
What's going on? Are you sick?
我覺得我應該是宿醉
I think I'm hung over.
宿醉  你就只喝了兩杯啤酒
How could you be hung over? You had two beers.
昨晚我送你回來后你又喝什么了
What else did you have after I dropped you off last night?
什么都沒喝
Nothing.
你頭痛嗎
Do you have a headache?
頭痛欲裂
Wicked.
想吐嗎
You feel like throwing up?
有點想
Considering it.
我這就給卡西迪博士打電話
I'm calling Dr. Cassidy.
真好  那要不要順便給我媽也打個電話
Oh, great, why don't you call my mom while you're at it?
我沒事的
I'll be fine.
我只需要來點番茄汁
I just need tomato juice,
醬油  再來點花生醬就行了
some soy sauce, and some peanut butter.
沃恩家的秘方
A Vaughn family recipe.
我都要吐了
Okay, I'm gonna throw up now.
怎么了  美國土著還舔自己吐的口水
What? The native Americans licked their own spit
來對付宿醉呢
to cure a hangover.
西西里人吃干牛鞭
Sicilians eat dried bull penis.
別說了
Stop talking.
換衣服去  我在外面等你
Just get dressed. I'll wait outside.
至于德國人
The Germans --
我聽不見
I can't hear you.
三名死者分別為約瑟夫·伯納德
The three men dead are Joseph Bernard,
聯調局分管國內的副局長
deputy director of the FBI for domestic ops,
他的保鏢
along with his security man,
和亞歷山大·哈奇上校  美國中央司令部
and Colonel Alexander Hatcher, former head of intelligence
在中東的前情報主管
for the U.S. Central command in the middle east.
哈奇  他已經退休...
Hatcher? He's been retired for --
五年了
Five years.
他們怎么認識對方的
How do they know each other?
伯納德當聯邦調查員之前在網絡軍隊待過
Bernard was in army intel before he went to the FBI.
哈奇是他的指揮官
Hatcher was his commanding officer.
所以  這算是社交見面嗎
So, the meet was social?
聯邦調查局的規矩是
FBI regs are
伯納德應該記錄所有會面
that Bernard should put all meetings on the books,
包括社交會面
even social.
這次會面卻沒有記錄
This one wasn't.
好  請注意看右下角
Okay, if you look at the bottom right
能看到一個肩膀
of the surveillance video, you see a shoulder.
沒錯  那肯定是槍手
Yeah, that has to be our shooter.
臨近的走廊
The camera on the adjoining corridor
有可能拍到這家伙的攝像機被關閉了
that would've seen this guy was switched off.
幾秒鐘后  這臺也被關了
A few seconds later, this one goes dead, too.
-有人在幫他開路  -沒錯
- Someone cleared his path. - Exactly.
這服務員并沒有加入奇怪的政治團體的記錄
The waiter has no record of strange political affiliations.
華盛頓地鐵報采訪了他
D.C. Metro interviewed him,
他表示自己是9點15分離開房間的
and he claims he left the room at 9:15,
當時沒發現廊上有人
and didn't notice anyone in the hallway.
不管是誰干的  都是個厲害人物
Oh, whoever did this has mad skills.
酒店的房卡系統沒留下任何痕跡
The hotel's key-card system was wiped clean.
罪案現場小組也沒發現任何指紋
And our crime-scene team found no prints,
沒有彈殼或者纖維殘留
no shell casings or fibers,
也沒有被害人以外的DNA
and no DNA other than the victims'.
我進入系統了
I'm in their system now.
等等
Wait a second.
你看到什么人了嗎
You see somebody?
是的
Yeah.
我看到他了
Think I got him.
加布里爾  你能認出他嗎
Gabriel, do you recognize him?
是誰
Who is it?
是我
It's me.
加布里爾·沃恩
Gabriel Vaughn
美國網戰司令部特工
三角洲一級作戰部隊
YYeTs人人影視
┌
┐
└
┘
■
┌
┐
└
┘
本字幕由
人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作
任何商業盈利行為
我國戰功最卓著的士兵之一
One of our nation's most decorated soldiers.
他是位英雄
He's a hero,
┌
┐
└
┘
■
┌
┐
└
┘
翻譯
衛老哥
CS小明漫畫家
貝貝
章魚X
木淺薰
小花豆
而現在他是我們最秘密的武器
and now our country's most secret weapon.
加布里爾擁有一種極其罕見的突變基因
Gabriel possesses a rare genetic mutation
┌
┐
└
┘
■
┌
┐
└
┘
翻譯
吃貨丁小七
艾瑞卡
姚小事兒
時間軸
小式
密思恩
貝貝
基因匹配
使我們能夠在他的大腦里植入微芯片
That allowed us to implant a microchip in his brain.
我們將他的大腦直接與信息網絡聯通
We connected his mind directly to the information grid.
互聯網
電話
衛  星
┌
┐
└
┘
■
┌
┐
└
┘
這是人類可望而不可及的
It's something the chip does that nobody expected.
校對
油炸電風扇
木淺薰
我可以在腦中重現事發時的虛擬場景
I can create a virtual snapshot of an event in my mind
┌
┐
└
┘
■
┌
┐
└
┘
特效
8T
并穿行其中
and then walk through it.
就像是虛擬的證據墻一樣
It's like a virtual evidence wall.
后期
寶寶
在美國網戰司令部
At U.S. Cyber Command,
我們為他組建了一支特別小隊
We created a highly specialized unit around him...
莉莉安·斯特蘭德
美國網戰司令部主任
衛星就位倒數  五
Satellite in five.
并安排了一名特工保護他
...and assigned an agent to protect him.
萊利·尼爾
美國網戰司令部特工
前特勤局探員
┌
┐
└
┘
■
他們有槍
Gun!
┌
┐
└
┘
總監
紫玉
他是第一個擁有
He's the first of his kind --
下一代智能的人
The next evolution of intelligence.
智能緝兇
第一季 第十二集
報告情況
Status report.
芯片在正常范圍內工作
The chip's functioning within normal parameters.
沒有可發現異常
No anomalies that we can find.
什么叫可發現異常
That you can find? The hell does that mean?
沒什么  沒什么意思
Nothing. It doesn't mean anything.
你不會認為真是我干的吧
You don't think I did this.
當然不會
No. Of course not.
我可沒殺人
I didn't kill anyone.
沒人覺得是你干的
No one here thinks that you did.
但是國家情報局長正趕過來
But the director of national intelligence is on his way over,
而我們得向他證明這一點
and he will need us to prove that.
所以現在  我要把目前所知的都擺上臺面
So right now, I need everything we know out on the table,
就從昨晚你去了哪開始
starting with where you were last night.
他跟我在一起
He was with me.
整晚嗎
All night?
不是吧  你們倆
Shut up.
不是  不是那樣的
No. Not like that.
只是下班后去吃個晚飯  喝點啤酒
Grabbed dinner and a beer after work.
然后我和萊利就回家了
Then I went home and Riley went home.
各回各家  像以往一樣
Separate homes, like we always do.
那時開始你就是一個人了  沒有證人能確認嗎
Then you were alone. No witness to corroborate?
-確認什么  -你的不在場證明
- Corroborate what? - Your alibi.
他為什么需要不在場證明
Why would he need an alibi?
很明顯不是他干的
He obviously didn't do this.
-莉莉安  -怎么了
- Lillian. - What is it?
你怎么不接電話
You're not answering your phone.
今天早上我頭痛來著
I had a headache this morning.
頭痛
A headache?
你怎么沒報告
You're supposed to report that.
什么樣的頭痛
What kind of a headache?
就是宿醉的那種頭痛
The kind you get from drinking too much.
真的嗎
Is that true?
我也不知道  應該是吧
I don't know. Y-yes, I guess so.
昨晚發生什么你都不記得了  對吧
You don't remember anything about last night, do you?
-莉莉安  -干嘛
- Lillian. - What is it?
怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
尼爾探員
Agent Neal,
請你放下武器
remove your hand from your weapon now.
亞當
Adam!
抱歉  莉莉安
I'm sorry, Lillian.
沃恩探員  請站起來
Agent Vaughn, on your feet, please.
你要指控他嗎
Are you charging him with something?
我們暫時稱之為保護性拘禁
For now, we're calling it protective custody.
我們只是要保證特工的安全
We're keeping our asset safe.
就是  感覺非常安全呢
Yeah, this feels real safe.
令人震驚都不足以表達我的心情
Outrageous doesn't begin to describe it.
你應該很熟悉在我們的機制里
You're well aware of the mechanisms in place
會發生這樣的事情
for events like this.
相互制衡  沒錯  我記得
Checks and balances, yes, I remember.
我還記得有種東西叫禮節
I also remember such a thing as courtesy.
禮節
Courtesy?
禮節應該是分享視頻中你的實驗室結果
Courtesy would be sharing your lab results on that video.
加布里爾在渲染中看到自己后
After Gabriel saw himself on the render,
你的人分析視頻  證實他的行為
your people analyzed the video and confirmed what he did.
你又是怎么知道的  杰弗
And how would you know that, Jeff?
你又在監視我們嗎
Are you spying on us again?
我知道是因為我們的分析人員發現了同樣的事情
I know that because our analysis came up with the same thing.
現在就我所知  只有兩種可能情況
Now, there are only two scenarios, as far as I can tell.
一種是加布里爾去了文德爾酒店
The first is that Gabriel went to the Windall Hotel,
有計劃有預謀地殘害了那些人
sentient and premeditated, and killed those men in cold blood.
荒唐
Ridiculous.
他有什么可能的動機嗎
What motive could he possibly have?
五年前
Until five years ago,
哈奇上校還是中央司令部的副指揮
Colonel Hatcher was the Deputy Commander of CENTCOM.
所以呢
So?
孟買襲擊后
So, he led the response team
是他指揮的應急小隊
after the attack in Mumbai.
是他讓殺害加布里爾妻子的兇手逃走了
He let the man who killed Gabriel's wife escape.
這個動機充分嗎
How's that for motive?
你說有兩種情況
You said there were two scenarios.
另一種是什么
What's the other?
芯片被黑
The chip was hacked
加布里爾受到他人的遠程操縱
and Gabriel was operated remotely by someone else.
芯片不能控制他做出
The chip can't make him do things
平時不會做的事情
that he wouldn't normally do.
有些人服了安眠藥
Some people take a sleeping pill,
然后半夜起床做出
get up in the middle of the night,
各種他們平時不會做的事情
do all sorts of things they wouldn't normally do.
但他們并沒受到遠程操縱
But they're not remotely operated.
加布里爾不是機器人
Gabriel is not a robot.
因為計劃中的芯片
"Because the proposed chip
利用的是先進的光遺傳學技術
"would utilize advanced optogenetics
將電腦代碼轉換成大腦信號再轉換回來
"to convert computer code to brain signals and back again,
所以總會有惡意侵入引起
"there will always be a risk that a malicious hack
分裂式大腦活動的風險
could enable a dissociated cerebral action."
通俗來說
In colloquial terms,
理論上  主體是可以被遠程操縱的
the subject could, in theory, be remotely operated.
這段話記錄在十年前
That was written 10 years ago
一篇名叫"論發條計劃的前景"的機密報告中
in a classified report entitled "The Potential of Clockwork"
作者是希恩多·卡西迪博士
by Dr. Shenandoah Cassidy.
跟我解釋下  什么叫分裂式大腦活動
Explain to me what a dissociated cerebral action is.
由于大腦特定區域向人類意識的信號堵塞
A hallucination whereby signals are blocked from certain areas
而產生的幻覺
of the brain to the conscious mind.
但是芯片被黑
But this notion that the chip could be hacked
導致加布里爾被迫實施謀殺的情況
and Gabriel could be made to commit a murder,
在科學上是不可能的  對嗎
that's scientifically impossible, correct?
我們對付的到底是什么
What are we dealing with?
這個項目仍在測試中  莉莉安
The program is still in beta, Lillian.
我們每天都在學習了解
We're learning things every day.
他被別人控制了嗎
Is he under someone else's control?
你要知道我們有異常堅固的防火墻
You'll recall we built a very robust firewall.
不要避重就輕  回答我的問題
Just answer the question.
是有一定的可能
It's within the realm of possibility.
事實上  我們現在還不能確定
The truth is, we just can't know for sure.
抱歉  我知道你現在也很難過  尼爾特工
I'm sorry. I know that must've been hard for you, Agent Neal.
我難過的是看到忠誠的缺乏
What's hard is seeing how little loyalty there is.
忠誠
Loyalty?
真是個有趣的詞
That's an interesting word.
它對你意味著什么
What does it mean to you?
支持  奉獻  承諾
Support. Dedication. Commitment.
特勤局那句話怎么說的
What's that saying at the secret service?
九成精力保護當事人  一成精力解決問題
90% to the client, 10% to the problem.
恕我直言  長官
All due respect, Sir,
我并沒有把加布里爾看成我的當事人
I don't consider Gabriel my client.
他是我的搭檔
I consider him my partner.
我的對面曾坐著很多不愿坦白的人
I've sat across from a lot of men who weren't willing to confess,
但最終  他們都醒悟了
but eventually, they all come around.
不過這里不是吉布提的黑獄
Except this isn't some black site in Djibouti
而我也不是一個
and I'm not an 18-year-old kid
被你拘留兩周的18歲小孩
you dropped in a hole for two weeks.
你覺得現在耍小聰明能救你嗎
You think your parlor tricks are gonna save you here?
不  我沒覺得  但我確定一件事
No, I don't... But I do know one thing.
什么
What's that?
從你的檔案來看
Judging from your files,
你比我更有嫌疑  實施這場謀殺
you're more likely to have committed this murder than I am.
你知道當莉莉安第一次
Do you know that when Lillian first brought your file to me
讓我把你的檔案拿給總統時
and asked me to take it to the president,
我就表示了深深的質疑
I had serious doubts.
你的經驗和英勇顯然不是問題所在
Your experience and bravery certainly weren't in question,
問題是你很年輕  而且是位女性
but you were young and you were a woman.
我擔心你倆間會有
I had concerns about the possibility
產生情感聯系的可能
of an emotional bond forming between the two of you.
莉莉安險些跟我翻臉
Lillian nearly took my head off,
說我是性別歧視主義
said I was being sexist.
而且我還擔心
I also had concerns
你殺掉你繼父的事
about the fact that you killed your stepfather.
他只是我母親的男友而已
He was my mother's boyfriend.
你只有15歲
You were 15 years old,
但你卻毫不猶豫地打死了他
yet you didn't hesitate to put him down.
-不對  -不是嗎
- Not true. - It's not?
我猶豫了
I hesitated.
所以第一槍打偏了
That's why the first bullet missed.
但這個錯誤我沒有犯過第二次
I've never made the same mistake again.
當時你聲稱是正當防衛
At the time, you claimed it was self-defense.
-本來就是  -其實
- It was. - Truth is...
你是在保護別的人  你母親
you were defending someone else -- your mother.
您想說什么  長官
What is your point, sir?
你的血液里有種保護的本能
That protection was always in your blood.
讓我不禁琢磨
Makes me wonder...
你會為了保護加布里爾做出什么樣的事
how far would you go to protect Gabriel?
我需要請律師嗎
Do I need a lawyer?
你該請
Yes, you do.
但你要先接受測謊
But first, you have to pass a polygraph.
如果能讓你好受些  我不認為是你做的
If it's any consolation, I don't think you did it --
至少不是有意的
not consciously, anyway.
你們搞錯了
This is insane.
我現在本應去追查真相
I should be out there right now finding answers.
你哪也不能去
You're not going anywhere.
你哪也不能去的原因是
And you're not going anywhere
你是件非常致命的武器  但卻不受控制
because you're a dangerous weapon that can't be controlled.
據我所知
As far as I'm concerned,
你也只有在把腦子里的芯片取出來之后
you'll have that chip ripped out of your head
才能走出這里
before you walk out of here.
我就覺得你會這么說
I had a feeling you were gonna say that.
抱歉了
Sorry.
紅色警報  加布里爾·沃恩逃跑了
Code red. Gabriel Vaughn has escaped.
快進來
Get in.
萊利  你在干什么
Riley, what the hell are you doing?
你是想進這輛車還是想進監獄
Do you want to go to prison or you want to get in?
你  不許動
Hey! Hey, you! Stop!
站在那不許動
Stop where you are!
你現在還堅信他完全可控嗎
You still doubt this man is out of control?
沒錯  我仍然堅信
Yes, I still doubt it.
我的人絕不會手下留情的
Well, my team will be weapons hot.
你不就挨了一拳嗎  杰弗  別那么小心眼
You took a punch, Jeff. Get over it.
等你那半機器人關進牢里后我就饒他一馬
I'll get over it when your cyborg is in a cage.
那你打算把他
Oh, and how long would you propose
關多久啊
keeping him in this cage?
關他一輩子  殺人犯就得這么對付
For the rest of his life, like any other murderer.
先別急  我們還是不確定加布里爾就是兇手
Easy, now. We're still not sure Gabriel did this.
他是不是兇手已經不重要了
Oh, it no longer matters whether or not he's guilty.
是嗎
Is that so?
他這一跑
He ran,
就已經證實了總統最大的擔憂
which proves the President's greatest fear,
也就是你沒本事控制住這件資產
that you cannot control and contain the asset.
但我能  而且會控制住的
But I can and will.
抱歉莉莉安  但杰弗說得對
I'm sorry, Lillian, but Jeff's right.
總統要求絕對的順從
The President expects absolute compliance.
他們是我的人  我能讓他們聽話的
These are my people. I can bring them in.
現在不是了
They were your people.
自此刻起
As of this moment,
莉莉安·斯特蘭德被調離領導職務
Lillian Strand has been removed from her command
等待通知
until further notice.
中情局局長杰弗里·泰塔祖代行網戰部長職權
DCI Jeffery Tetazoo is now acting head of Cybercom.
因此  現在將由他領導
As such, he will be leading the manhunt
對加布里爾·沃恩和萊利·尼爾的追捕行動
for Gabriel Vaughn and Riley Neal.
你們將對他絕對效忠
You will all give him your complete loyalty.
我說清楚了嗎
Do I make myself clear?
泰塔祖局長  你可以下達指令了
Director Tetazoo, C-doc is yours.
即便網戰司令部技術設備和實力非常強大
Even with the considerable technological might of Cybercom,
加布里爾也仍然占據優勢
Gabriel will have the advantage here.
但我希望兩位卡西迪博士能夠
But I'm going to rely on the doctors Cassidy
確保他的優勢得到有效抵消
to ensure that any advantage is minimized.
現在立即將中大西洋的空中力量
Let's begin by re-deploying all mid-atlantic drone
和衛星監視重新部署至特區周邊
and satellite coverage to the D.C. area.
我要求華盛頓市區的
I want every piece of silicon
每一臺電子設備都在監控之下
inside the D.C. metro area monitored --
取款機  交通系統那些  全部監視
ATMs, traffic systems, all of it.
我需要所有接入到上述系統的網絡地址
I want I.P. addresses accessing those systems
的實時記錄
recorded in real time,
任何無法識別的通訊協議須立即示警
and any anonymized protocols are to be flagged immediately.
只要加布里爾試圖使用芯片進入任何設備
If Gabriel tries to get eyes on something,
我都要馬上知道
I want to know about it.
你們均不得讓個人情感影響到你們的
You'll all put aside whatever personal feelings you have
追捕工作
and do your jobs.
任何形式的抗命都將被迅速處置
Any noncompliance will be dealt with swiftly
并予以嚴懲
and with extreme prejudice.
開始工作
Let's get to work.
-莉莉安  -會沒事的
- Lillian. - It'll be all right.
就這樣了嗎
So, this is happening.
小心
Easy.
有問題嗎  詹姆森特工
Do we have a problem here, Agent Jameson?
當然沒問題  能有啥問題
No. There's no problem, is there?
沒有  投入工作之前我只有一個問題
Nope. I just have one question so I'm clear.
本次行動有武力協議嗎
Is there a force protocol on this mission?
本次行動使用E-F武力協議
Force protocol is Echo-Foxtrot
對兩名在逃人員均適用
for both the asset and his accomplice.
他這是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
意思是我們這位代理網戰部長
It means the acting director of Cybercom
只求抓人  不論死活
doesn't care if he brings them in dead or alive.
這樣衛星就找不到這輛車了
This should keep the SUV out of satellite view.
GPS怎么辦
What about GPS?
離開網戰司令部時我就弄壞了
I disabled it when we left cybercom.
你接受過逃亡訓練嗎
You have practice being a fugitive?
有不少追蹤逃亡者的訓練
Plenty of practice hunting them.
現在怎么辦
So, now what?
在我把這事弄清前  別被抓到
Keep out of sight till I can figure this out.
是在我們把這事弄清前
Until we figure it out?
你得回去  萊利
You're going back, Riley.
回哪去
Back where?
他們要抓的是我  不是你
I'm the one they want, not you.
真高興我為你工作
Well, it's a good thing I don't work for you,
不然我就必須服從你的傻命令了
otherwise, I'd have to follow your dumb orders.
我可不打算毀了你的前程
I'm not gonna let you throw your career away.
在剛把我逃跑開出來的車藏起來之后嗎
As we cover up the getaway car I just drove?
有道理
Good point.
-我不后悔  -真的
- I have no regrets. - No?
你原本是保護總統的
You went from protecting the president
現在卻和一個失靈的機器人四處逃亡
to riding in blind with a malfunctioning robot?
機器人不會痛
Robots don't say "Ow."
你不是個殺人犯
You're not a murderer.
我親眼看到了  我在錄像里
I saw what I saw. I'm on that tape.
那是個構劃精巧的陰謀而已
It is a very sophisticated frame job.
我們都明白這點
We both know it.
是嗎
Do we?
是的
Yes, we do.
好吧
Well...
我們至少得考慮一下可能性
we at least have to consider the possibility.
那晚的事我一點也不記得了
I can't remember anything from that night,
而且我們都知道芯片并不可靠
And we both know the chip can be unreliable.
但你不是芯片
But you are not the chip.
你是個人
You're a man.
是我最...信任的人
A man I trust more than... any other.
里根總統
Look, President Reagan,
在華盛頓希爾頓酒店被槍擊
he was shot at the Washington Hilton.
幾個月之后
And for months afterwards,
有個人一直在事發地點徘徊
there was a man who paced the sidewalk where it happened.
他是調查那個案件的特勤局特工
He was a secret service agent who was investigating the case.
要想揭開真相
If we want to figure out the truth,
只有一個地方可去
there's only one place to go.
案發現場
The scene of the crime.
我們去文德爾酒店
We have to go to the Windall Hotel.
利蘭·斯特蘭德宅邸
華盛頓特區
不了  謝謝
No, I better not.
波旁酒最大的優點就是
You know, one of the nice things about bourbon
不一定要喝下  才能體會其香醇
is you don't actually have to drink it to enjoy it.
有時  只是拿在手里
Sometimes just holding it in your hand
都是種享受
can be comfort enough.
再說了  你還能做什么呢
Plus, what else do you have to do?
謝謝
Nice.
讓我停職是個錯誤
Removing me was a mistake.
沒人比我更了解加布里爾
Nobody knows Gabriel like I do.
我可以把他安全的帶回來
I can bring him back safely.
你得到什么消息了嗎
What are you hearing?
什么也沒有
Nothing.
你在騙我嗎
Are you lying to me?
是的
Yes.
實話實說  我是不是被開除了
Truth, dad. Am I out?
還不確定
It's not clear yet.
發條計劃一直都很脆弱
The Clockwork program's always been vulnerable.
對于幾個知情人來說
For those in the know,
這個科學技術本身就很可怕
the science is frightening,
它的力量更是驚人
the power is breathtaking,
預算也是個天文數字
and the budget's astronomical.
這些讓你成為了他們的眼中釘
That all adds up to a target on your back.
所以這是泰塔祖的私仇了
Well, this is personal with Tetazoo.
從一開始他就想接管發條計劃
He's been out to get Clockwork since day one.
別再糾結過去了
Get up off the ground already.
爸  我不是來找你上課的
You know, dad, I didn't come here for a lesson.
我來是
I came here --
要什么
For what?
要個擁抱嗎
You need a hug?
我才不需要擁抱
No, I don't need a hug.
那就好  那就開始按我教給你的做
Good. Then start doing what I taught you to do.
怎么干  他們已經開除我了
How? They kicked me out.
那又怎樣  他們困住你手腳了嗎
So what? Did they give you a lobotomy?
問個問題不需要許可
You don't need permission to ask questions.
我這不是正在問嗎
I am asking questions.
你沒有  至少沒有問到點子上
No, you're not. Not the right ones.
你離加布里爾和發條計劃太近了
You're too close to Gabriel and Clockwork
看不到全局
to see past any of it.
你的目標在遠處
On the other side of it is your real target.
才是你的機會
That's where your brass ring is.
真兇
The murders.
一個曾經能夠獲取
A former military intelligence officer
我們最敏感的中東情報的前軍方情報官員
who once had access to our most sensitive middle east intel
現在要和我們的
has an off-book meeting
聯邦調查局副局長私下會面
with the deputy director of the FBI.
為什么
Why?
我們得找個交通工具
We need to find a vehicle.
面包車可算不上是交通工具
A minivan is not a vehicle.
看窗戶
Look at the window.
衛星控制系統  你的芯片可以控制
There's an on-sat system. You can chip it.
你真的要偷這輛車
You really want to steal this?
只是借用
Well, borrow.
而且就我們今天犯下的罪行里
And, you know, on the list of felonies
俠盜飛車
that we've committed today,
可以算是最微不足道的了
Grand Theft Auto, it's way at the bottom.
當我們最終被發現并且逮捕的時候
When we're finally found and arrested,
你想讓所有人知道我偷了輛面包車嗎
You want everybody to know we stole a minivan?
我們就不能找個福特野馬之類的嗎
Can't we find a mustang or something?
因果報應啊
Bad karma.
你好  加布里爾
Hello, Gabriel.
再見  加布里爾
Goodbye, Gabriel.
祝你好運
And good luck.
能半小時后見面嗎
在我們開始之前  你們要知道
Before we start, you all need to know
光是和我一起坐在這里就能致你們入獄
that just sitting here with me can land you in prison.
如果你們現在起身離開
If you get up and leave right now,
我完全可以理解
I would completely understand.
想要點什么嗎
Hey, folks. Can I get you anything?
一杯巧克力奶昔
A chocolate shake.
怎么了  他們這兒奶昔很正宗
What? They make a mean milkshake.
-你來過這里嗎  -沒有
- You've been here before? - Nope.
我們的奶昔很正宗
爽滑棉柔
的確不錯
They're really good.
請給我一杯草莓奶昔
strawberry for me, please.
香草奶昔
Vanilla.
奶油硬糖奶昔
Butterscotch.
馬上就來
Coming right up.
順便說一句  我今天已經犯了重罪
Incidentally, I've committed a felony already today.
加布里爾似乎在網絡中出現了
Gabriel may have popped up on the grid.
某個人有一份計劃
Someone had an agenda here.
不只是刺殺這么簡單
This wasn't just an assassination.
但是我們怎么能知道呢
But how do we know that?
因為本來有更簡單的方法
Because there are easier ways to do it,
即便沒有加布里爾的參與  方法也是有的
even without the Gabriel component, if there is one.
這是個安裝著先進安保系統的特區酒店
It's a D.C. Hotel with an advanced security system,
更別提還有三百位賓客走來走去
not to mention 300 guests coming and going.
對不起
Sorry.
聽著
Look...
我們這行  三件事會給你惹來殺身之禍
Three things get you killed in our business --
真實身份  知道的事情  擁有的東西
Who you are, what you know, or what you have.
哈奇已經不再干這行了
Hatcher is not in the game anymore,
這讓他成為了一個謎  而不是伯納德
which makes him the mystery, not Bernard.
有沒有可能是哈奇正在執行
Could Hatcher have been working
我們所不知道的臥底行動
some covert op we're not aware of?
不是  他的名字在情報中心
No, his name doesn't appear in any roster
三千個注冊機構的花名冊中
in any of the 3,000 registered organizations
都沒有出現
In the U.S. intelligence community.
表面上看  哈奇沒有重要到
On the surface, Hatcher isn't important enough
讓人費如此大的麻煩來殺了他
for someone to go to all this trouble to kill.
這說明要不然他知道些什么
That means that he either knew something
要不然他擁有什么  才讓他變得如此重要
or he had something that made him important.
詹姆森和我會弄清楚那到底什么的
Jameson and I are gonna figure out what that was.
那我們倆呢
What about us?
你和尼爾森要弄清楚
You and Nelson are gonna figure out
加布里爾的臉是怎么出現在那個錄像中的
how it's possible that Gabriel's face is on that tape.
各位
Guys...
如果真是加布里爾所為呢
What if Gabriel did do it?
衛斯理和泰塔祖
Weatherly and Tetazoo
或許無法給他們無罪推定
May not be affording him the presumption of innocence,
但我們應該以無罪來推定
But we owe him at least that much.
-好吧  我明天請病假  -不要
- All right. I'm gonna call in sick tomorrow. - No.
你們要去上班并向泰塔祖報告  所有人
You will go in and you will report to Tetazoo -- all of you.
只要你們還在內部
As long as you're on the inside,
我們就可以利用我們需要的一切資源
we'll have access to everything we need,
你們也會知道泰塔祖什么時候
and you'll know when Tetazoo is close
快要找到加布里爾和萊利了
to finding Gabriel and Riley.
我斗膽問一句
Dare I ask...
你聽到他的消息了嗎
You heard from him?
沒有
No.
但是如果要我猜的話
But if I had to guess...
他們正在做和我們同樣的事情
...I think they're doing the same thing we're doing.
別擔心  沒人會看見我們
Don't worry. Nobody can see us.
我在這些監控上正放著循環錄像呢
I'm running a loop on those right now.
在渲染上  我站在這里
In the cyber render, I was standing here...
等著
Waiting.
所以  保安是房間里
So, the security guard
唯一有武器的人
was the only one in the room who was armed.
但他沒有拔出過武器
He never drew his weapon.
所以他是第一個中槍的人
So he was the first one shot.
他站在這里
He was standing over here,
說明子彈是從這里射出的
So that means shot came from about here.
所以不管這個人是誰
So whoever it was...
就站在哈奇身前
Was standing right in front of Hatcher.
他在開香檳
He was opening the champagne.
所以射手向屋里另一個持槍的人
So, the shooter puts one in the back
法醫鑒定報告
后背開了一槍
of the only other gun in the room,
轉向哈奇  近距離射擊
Turns to Hatcher, close range --
子彈從下頜下面射入
one right under the chin.
伯納德應該是下一個目標
Bernard would've been next.
哈奇有多高
How tall was Hatcher?
一米七
5'8".
跟我一樣高
My height.
你
You.
剛把保安放倒  舉起槍
Just took out the security guard, your gun's raised.
轉身  迅速向哈奇開槍
You turn, quickly shoot Hatcher.
看看這個彈道
Look at the trajectory.
你要蹲著開槍才行
You would've had to have been crouching.
你太高了
you're too tall.
不可能是你
It couldn't have been you.
如果不是我
Well, if it wasn't me,
為什么我會出現在視頻里
how did I end up on that video?
卡西迪宅邸
我去泡一壺咖啡  今晚可有的忙了
I'll put on a pot of coffee. Gonna be a long night.
我們會用到
We need everything we have
涉及數碼攝像機的一切技術
on digital video camera technology,
CCD傳感器  視頻壓縮
CCD chips, video compression.
我做好三明治就開始干活
I'm on it as soon as I make a sandwich.
可你剛吃過
You just ate.
你有哈瓦蒂干酪嗎
Ooh! Do you have any havarti cheese?
我就喜歡
I just love...
清理工作間
"清理工作間"
"Tidy up the workshop"?
你說什么
Excuse me?
這是誰的筆跡
Whose handwriting is this?
爸
Dad.
退后
Stay back.
晚上好  伙計們
Evening, boys.
你們在這里干什么
What are you doing here?
你們沒事吧  我們擔心死了
Are you guys okay? We were so worr--
尼爾森  站著別動
Nelson! Stay where you are.
博士  發生什么事了
Doc, what's the matter?
這是什么情況
What's going on?
1973年8月1日
On August 1, 1973,
我在艾斯伯瑞公園木板路上吻了一個女孩
I kissed a girl under the Asbury Park boardwalk.
好樣的
Okay. Good for you.
-你在說什么  -她叫什么名字
- What are you talking about? - What was her name?
我不懂你的意思  你沒事吧
I'm confused. Are you okay?
她叫什么名字  加布里爾
What was her name, Gabriel?
羅琳  她叫羅琳
Loraine. Her name was Loraine.
這是正確答案嗎
Is that the right answer?
沒錯
Yeah.
感謝上帝
Thank God.
-真的是你  -如假包換
- It's you in there, isn't it? - All me.
不好意思  我必須確認清楚
I'm sorry, guys. I had to be certain.
那個名字從未出現在任何數據庫里
That name has never occurred in any database.
我從來沒有對任何人透露過這件事
I've never written about it, I've never spoken about it
除了六年前一個晚上我告訴了加布里爾
Except to Gabriel one night six years ago
我當時香檳喝得有點多
when I'd, uh, had a little too much champagne.
1973年8月1日
August 1, 1973?
你跟媽媽結婚那天
That's the day you married mom...
她可不叫羅琳
Whose name's not Loraine!
-說來話長  -那是肯定的
- It's a long story... - I'm sure it is.
這個我們晚點再說
...which we will talk about some other time.
伙計們  集中點注意力
Boys. Can we focus?
不是加布里爾干的
Look, Gabriel didn't do this.
當然  當然不是他
No. Of -- of course he didn't.
他不可能做到
No, he couldn't have done it.
我們剛去了案發現場
We just walked the crime scene.
現場數據不成立
The math doesn't add up.
槍手要比他矮多了
The shooter was much shorter.
那太棒了
That's terrific.
等等  那視頻怎么解釋
Wait a second. Stop. What about the video?
存放視頻的硬盤
The hard drive that the image was stored on
從沒有被換過或者修改過
was never altered or tampered with.
有沒有可能視頻資源在到達硬盤前
Is it possible the incoming image was changed
就被換了
before it reached the hard drive?
博士  你想到什么了
Doc, what is it?
怎么就沒想到呢  沒錯
Stupid. Stupid! Yes!
安保攝像頭用了一種CCD感應器
The security camera uses a CCD sensor.
感應器上的每一個像素
Each pixel on that sensor
都對應著一個PMOS電容器
is represented by a P-doped MOS capacitor.
一旦光打到感應器上
When light hits the sensor,
光子就  -博士
- the photons... - Doctor.
你能講普通話嗎
Any chance of this being in English?
好吧  好吧  普通話  沒問題
Right. Right. English, yes. All right.
關于像素
Um, the pixels.
像素實際上就是電子脈沖
The pixels are really just an electronic pulse.
理論上  每個像素都能單獨被修改
Theoretically, each pixel could be individually modified
生成與進入的光子所代表的
to display a different image
完全不同的圖像
than the one represented by the incoming photons.
爸  看在上帝的份上
Dad, for the love of God, just get --
沒有別的方法來解釋了
There's no other way to say that!
想要做出實時改變
The trick is it would take enormous speed
需要超強的速度和處理能力
and processing power to do it in real time.
或許只有他的芯片能做到
His chip is probably the only one that can do it,
可是他為什么要陷害自己呢
and why would he frame himself?
不  不只他的芯片能做到
No. His chip is not the only one that could do it.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
美辰
Mei Chen.
我們必須找到她
We have to find her.
怎么找
How?
博士  你得幫我降低防火墻等級
Doc, I need you to lower my firewalls.
不  不  絕對不可能
No. No. Absolutely not.
上次引誘美辰進入你的網絡渲染
The last time we lured Mei Chen into one of your cyber renders,
我們差點失去你
we almost lost you.
如果我們不能證明是美辰陷害了加布里爾
If we can't prove that Mei Chen framed Gabriel,
我們就已經失去他了
we've already lost him.
伙計們  代理服務器已停止
Okay, kids. Proxy server's deactivated.
轉移到了應用層面
Moving to the application layer.
過濾功能被部分禁用了
Filtering is now partially disabled.
就是這里  讓你覺得這是個壞主意分嗎
Isn't this the part where you tell me what a bad idea this is?
可你還是無視我  堅持己見
And then you ignore me and do it anyway.
天啊  我們就不能先做事嗎
Oh, my. Guys, can we just do this already, please?
至少等到防火墻失效了
as far as the firewall is down.
好了  你的芯片現在很容易被滲透
All right, your chip is now vulnerable to infiltration.
上帝保佑
Lord help us all.
沒有美辰的蹤跡
No sign of Mei Chen.
還能再降低我的防御系統嗎
What else can you do to lower my defenses?
再關一層
One more layer.
爸爸  這...
Dad. Just...
我們的計劃是降低防護然后請君入甕
The trick is leaving you exposed enough to lure her in
不是讓你毫無防備使她攻陷芯片
but not so unprotected that she can actually compromise the chip.
別擔心  博士  我知道如何引她上鉤
Don't worry, Doc. I know how to get her attention.
我還擔心你把我忘了呢
I was afraid you'd forget about me.
以謀殺陷害提醒我  真是個好辦法
Framing me for murder's a nice way to remind me.
我想你了
I missed you.
你為什么這么做
Why'd you do it?
公事公辦罷了
It's just business.
沒有私仇
Nothing personal.
公事  有人花錢雇你嗎
Business? So someone paid you to do this.
我不做無償服務  除了這個
I don't do anything for free, except this.
你想在我們之間建立的墻實在太假了
The walls you try to put up between us are so artificial.
我們是一類  我和你
We're the same, you and me.
你冷血殺害了三個人
You murdered three people in cold blood.
在一個現實里  是的
In one reality, yes.
不止一個現實嗎
Is there more than one?
你說呢
You tell me.
我們比他們強大太多了
We're too powerful for them.
你太過強大
You're too powerful.
所以他們不能留你活口
Which is why they can't let you survive.
看看你的朋友們多快就背棄了你
Look how quickly your friends turned on you,
他們現在正在追捕你
and now they're hunting you.
我是世上唯一你能分享這些的人
I'm the only person on earth you can share this with.
這是我們創造的現實
This reality is one we're making.
只有我們兩人
Just the two of us.
現在我們在彼此的腦海中
You're inside my mind right now, and I'm inside yours.
你能和她這樣分享嗎
Can you ever share something like this with her?
你不會寂寞嗎  加布里爾
Don't you get lonely, Gabriel?
會
Yes.
我能給你想要的一切
I can give you everything you want.
我能帶給你前所未見的
I can show you things you haven't seen yet,
那些他們還未告訴過你的能力
things that you can do that they haven't told you about.
找到她了
Got her.
你讓我別無選擇
You didn't leave me with much of a choice.
你不會想與我為敵  至少不是現在
You don't want me as your enemy. Not now.
你陷害我謀殺
You framed me for murder.
這可不算友誼之舉啊
That doesn't exactly make us friends.
你有很多事情不知道
There are things you don't know.
什么事情
What things?
你說什么
Excuse me?
什么我們不知道的事
What things don't we know?
放我走我就告訴你
Let me go, and I'll tell you.
我不愛賭博
I've never been a gambler,
不過這聽起來勝算不大
but that sounds like a pretty bad bet.
好樣的  加布里爾
Well done, Gabriel.
我不知道你干了什么使她分心
I don't know what you did to distract her,
但你讓她沒注意到我們在追蹤她
but you kept her from sensing our trace.
萊利抓到她了
Riley has her.
我知道你做了什么  你色誘她了
I know what you did. You dropped some sexy on her.
肯定還很少兒不宜
I expect copious details.
為了科學  爸爸
It's for science, dad.
他告訴過你我們的渲染嗎
Has he told you about our renders?
沒有
No.
我猜他也不會
No. I suppose he wouldn't.
說來聽聽
Spare me.
這么說吧
Let's just say
他比我想象中更如狼似虎
he's more carnivorous than I was expecting.
不想戳破你的少女心
I hate to disappoint you,
但他那是在和你演戲
but he was playing you.
沒人能演得那么好
No one plays that well.
關于"漫布"你知道些什么
What can you tell me about the Flood?
"漫布"嗎
The Flood?
是個伊朗人的程序
It's an Iranian program.
哈奇對它癡狂
Hatcher was obsessed with it.
幾乎傾其整個職業生涯
Pretty much cost him his career.
我怎么不知道這些
Why don't I know anything about it?
因為這是個謎
Because it's a myth.
那三個人可不是因為謎才被殺
Three people were not murdered because of a myth.
請講
Yes?
莉莉安  我是加布里爾
Lillian, it's Gabriel.
加布里爾
Gabriel.
是美辰干的
It was Mei Chen.
美辰嗎
Mei Chen?
是她殺了那些人  還嫁禍于我
She's the one that killed those men and framed me.
還有  莉莉安  我們抓到她了
And, Lillian, we have her.
-把她帶來  -不行
- Well, bring her in. - No.
什么意思  為什么不行
What do you mean? Why not?
我不想冒險把她交給泰塔祖
I'm not gonna risk handing her over to Tetazoo.
我明白
Understood.
錢德勒廣場  一個小時內來見我
Chandler square. Can you meet me in an hour?
我會去的
I'll be there.
-一個人來  莉莉安  -當然
- Alone, Lillian. - Of course.
詹姆森特工
Agent Jameson!
如果你按下發送鍵
If you click "Send" on that phone,
你以后就在牢里蹲個二十年吧
you will spend the next 20 years in a concrete box.
利蘭·斯特蘭德宅邸
華盛頓特區
八十年代初  在他給中央司令部搞情報之前
Back in the early '80s before he ran intel for Centcom,
哈奇還是個在國防情報局的外勤小特工
Hatcher was a field agent with Defense Intelligence.
他對"漫布"著了迷
He apparently became fixated on the Flood.
怎么了
What is it?
這就像是尼斯湖水怪
It's the Loch Ness Monster,
大腳野人  外星人綁架
bigfoot, alien abductions.
只是眾多傳說中的一個
It's a legend, like any other,
古老的幽靈在昏暗嗆人的屋子里低語的那種
whispered in dark, smoky rooms by old spooks.
現在我們就和幽靈呆在一個昏暗嗆人的屋子里
I guess we're in a dark, smoky room with an old spook.
好吧
Okay.
在1979年的伊朗人質危機之后
During the Iran Hostage Crisis in 1979,
我們開始從薩瓦馬[前伊朗情報機構]
we started hearing rumblings of a crazy idea
聽到很多瘋狂的想法
bubbling up through the Iranian Savama.
這后來成為了他們情報單位的名字
That was the name of their intelligence agency then.
他們的想法是向美國植入潛伏特工
The idea was to insert sleeper agents in U.S. society.
像蘇聯人那樣
Like the soviets.
有一個關鍵的區別
With one key difference --
招募方式
recruitment.
蘇聯人只對境內招募
The soviets always recruited from within their borders
并試圖教育自己的人民
and attempted to teach their people
如何融入我們的社會
how to blend in with our society,
這通常會帶來災難性的后果
often with disastrous results.
按照推測  伊朗人有個新奇的想法
Supposedly, the Iranians had a novel idea --
在美國本土招募特工
recruit in America.
找到那些同情伊朗的人
Find people who either were sympathetic to Iran
或者是那些可以用錢買通
or who could be made sympathetic
讓他們同情伊朗的人
by fulfilling certain financial needs.
最終實現了嗎
Did it ever come to fruition?
不大可能
Unlikely.
那如果哈奇找到了這個神話的證據
Well, what if Hatcher found proof of this myth
而這給他帶來殺身之禍
and it got him killed,
也殃及到了他要把證據移交給的
along with the deputy director of the FBI
聯邦調查局副局長
he was turning it over to?
我覺得這是個重大突破
I'd say that's a big leap.
我們的職責就是尋找突破  你教我的
We're in the business of big leaps. You taught me that.
我去把我的人和美辰一起帶來
I'm gonna bring my people in along with Mei Chen.
她不會合作的
She won't cooperate.
我會讓她合作的
I'll make her cooperate.
小公雞
Rooster...
你小心點
...you be careful.
她來了
There she is.
看起來她是按約一個人來的  很好
Looks like she came alone like we agreed. Good.
你打算怎么做
So, how do you want to do this?
跟緊  盯著她  我去和莉莉安說句話
Stay close, keep an eye on her. I'll check in with Lillian.
你犯了個可悲的錯誤
You're making a tragic mistake.
你覺得你是他們的一員  但你不是
You think you're one of them. You're not.
你對他們而言只是個硬件
You're just a piece of hardware to them.
你本不用那么孤單的  你自己選擇的
You didn't have to be so alone. You made that choice.
不  我不是
No, I didn't.
有人替我做了選擇  把它放在我腦袋里
Someone else made a choice to put this in my head --
你英明神武的卡西迪博士  記得嗎
your heroic Dr. Cassidy, remember?
他選擇了救自己的命  代價就是我的命
He chose to save his own life at the expense of mine.
你的頭腦都被你引以為傲的
Your mind is spinning along with that uniquely American
典型美式道德羅盤束縛住了
moral compass you're all so proud of.
夠了  走
That's enough. Let's go.
-她不是一個人  -閉嘴
- She's not alone. - Shut up.
這是個陷阱  加布里爾  看著我
It's a trap, Gabriel. Look at me.
這是個陷阱
This is a trap.
我沒察覺到任何無線電廣播
I'm not picking up any radio transmissions.
加布里爾
Gabriel...
她了解你的  知道嗎
She knows you. Remember?
這感覺不對
This doesn't feel right.
加布里爾
Gabriel!
找到那個狙擊手  活捉他
Find that shooter! I want him alive!
你算計我
You were set up on me!
你以為呢
What did you expect?
叫他們走  你為什么要殺他
Call them off! Why are you shooting at him?!
不是我們干的
That wasn't us.
你指望我相信嗎  叫他們走
You expect me to believe that? Call them off!
不是我們干的  莉莉安
It wasn't us, Lillian.
這沒道理  為什么莉莉安會
Doesn't make any sense. Why would Lillian --
他快不行了
He's not going to make it.
他會撐住的
He is going to make it!
長官  我們正在搜尋屋頂
We're checking rooftops right now, sir.
沒有狙擊手痕跡
No sign of the shooter.
-加布里爾呢  -也沒有  長官
- What about Gabriel? - Negative, sir.
找到他們  記住
Find them. Remember --
別用無線電和電子設備  去吧
no radios, nothing electronic. Go.
加布里爾  加布里爾
Gabriel. Gabriel.
我們不能待在這兒  這不安全
We can't stay here. It's not safe.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
你怎么知道他們會向我們開火
How did you know they'd fire on us?
你還沒明白  是嗎
You don't get it, do you?
一共開了兩槍  第二槍是射向你的
There were two shots fired. The last one was meant for you.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我怎么知道政府為什么要背叛你嗎
How did I know the government would turn on you?
你覺得是誰雇我來的
Who do you think hired me?
有人雇我來殺了那些人  然后栽贓給你
I was hired to kill those men and frame you for it.
就是你的政府雇的
Hired by your own government.
沒錯
That's right.
這比你能想象的
This is bigger and more insidious
還要陰險黑暗的多
than you can possibly fathom.
具體是誰雇你來的  給我個名字
Who hired you, exactly? Give me a name.
我們現在是一條繩上的了
We're on the same team now.
未完待續